A Guide to the Jordan Family Collection, 1752-1992 (bulk 1830-1930)
Library of Virginia
- Series III. Subject Files, 1781-1992., Extent: 16 boxes. (Box 39-54)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1851-1852. (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1853-1855. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1856-1859. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1860. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1862. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1863. (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1864. (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Slave Hire Receipts, 1834-1864. (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - C. B. Slaugh and Son, 1952. (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Smith Family Bible Records, 1781-1902. (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - H. B. Smith Machine Co., 1910. (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Southern Baptist Theological Seminary, 1867-1872. (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Southern Seminary, 1904. (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Spencer Heater Division, 1939-1940. (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Sphinx Motor Car Company, 1916. (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Splitdorf Electrical Company, 1914-1916. (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Stanley Works, 1917. (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Stationary. (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Stiff, William W., 1848-1854. (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Stinnett, Charles, 1938. (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Stock Certificates. (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Stock Subscriptions, 1889-1890. (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - Stratton, Richard H., 1853-1856, 1866. (Box 51, Folder 25)
  - Stratton, R. H. - Orders, 1854. (Box 51, Folder 26)
  - Suit Papers, 1854-1905. (Box 51, Folder 27-28)
  - Sullivan Machinery Company, 1913. (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Summons, 1854-1895. (Box 51, Folder 30)
  - Surveys. (Box 51, Folder 31)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1833-1835, 1842-1849. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1850-1857. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1860-1865. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1866-1869. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1870-1873. (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1874-1879. (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1880-1883. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1890-1899. (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1900-1909. (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1910-1919. (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1920-1929. (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1930-1932. (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1933-1936. (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1937-1939. (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1940-1949. (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1950-1959. (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1960-1961. (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Taylor and Brother (McDowell and Taylor), 1855-1856. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Terrell's Equipment Company, 1917. (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Trade, Business, and Calling Cards. 1 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Truslow, Levi - Work in Saddle Factory, 1889. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Tyree v. Tyree, 1902. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Valley Union Seminary, 1865-1855. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - James L. Vance and Co., 1895-1900. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Victoria Furnace - Lists of Balances, Inventory, etc., 1869-1871. (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - "Virginia Children's Hime Finder," vol. 8, no.1, (May, 1927) (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Garage, 1922-1930, 1937. (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Military Institute. (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Virginia National Bank - History, 1924. (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Waesche - Accounts and Receipts, 1858-1893. (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Waesche - Autograph Books, 1878-1881. (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Waesche - Correspondence, 1870-1888. (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Waesche - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Waesche - Miscellaneous. (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Walker Manufacturing Company, 1925. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Walls, Owen and Stambach Company, 1918. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Washington College, 1863. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Edmund Watson and Co., 1842-1844. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - W. H. Watson and Co. - Receipts, 1843. (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Wheeler and Wilson Manufacturing Co., 1881. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - W. G. White and Bros., 1848-1853. (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - White, William, 1857-1865. (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Wilbourn Patent, 1889-1894. (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Will of John T. Jordan, 1887. (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Will of Samuel F. Jordan, 1872. (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Will of Clifton H. Moore, 1951. (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Willson and Compton, 1868. (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Willson and Compton - Accounts, 1867-1867. (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Wilson and Barclay, 1854-1856. (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Witherow, Samuel - Plow Patent, 1843. (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Witt and Watkins, 1883. (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Woman's Auxiliary, 1938-1939. (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Wrappers. (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Wysong and Miles Company, 1905. (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - Young Men's Democratic Club Certificate, 1892. (Box 54, Folder 21)
- Series IV. Ledgers and Account Books, 1847-1938., Extent: 4 boxes and 69 volumes. (Box 55-58)
  There are ledgers, daybooks, time books, letter books, minute book, stock ledger, cash ledger, order books, and inventory ledgers. These volumes contain financial records for the following businesses or entities: Jordan and Jordan, Lexington Foundry, Buena Vista Furnace, Amherst Furnace, Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company, Lexington Mill, North River Canal, Buena Vista Cannery, North River Insurance Company, Buena Vista Hotel, and hardware business records of George W. Waesche. There are also four boxes containing small ledgers, memorandum books, account books, receipt books, time books, bank books, and catalogs and price lists from various companies and supply houses. For preservation purposes, the minute book and letter books of the Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company have been microfilmed (Misc. Reels 5399-5400).
  - Small Ledgers, Memorandum Books, Account Books, Receipt Books, Time Books. (Box 55-56)
  - Bank Books. (Box 57)
  - Catalogs and Price Lists. (Box 58)
  - Journal A (Jordan and Jordan), 1847-1849. (Volume 1)
  - Journal A (Jordan and Jordan), 1847-1850. (Volume 2)
  - Ledger, 1848-1852, 1866-1867. (Volume 3)
  - Ledger, 1848, 2887. (Volume 4)
  - Ledger (portion), 1853-1854. (Volume 5)
  - Ledger, 1854-1856. (Volume 6)
  - Lexington Foundry Ledger A, 1848-1852, 1856-1857. (Volume 7)
  - Lexington Foundry Ledger C, 1848-1852, 1852-1857. (Volume 8)
  - Lexington Foundry Day Book, 12 February 1856 - 23 May 1857. (Volume 9)
  - Buena Vista Furnace Day Book, 17 February 1857 - 27 September 1858. (Volume 10)
  - Negro Hires and Hands Time and Clothing Ledger, 1855-1865. (Volume 11)
  - Negro Ledger, 1857-1866. (Volume 12)
  - Receipt Book, 12 November 1867 - 10 June 1870. (Volume 13)
  - Ledger, 1878. (Volume 14)
  - Ledger, 1880-1891. (Volume 15)
  - Ledger (Ore Bank), 1865-1868. (Volume 16)
  - Ledger D (Ore Bank), 1868-1878. (Volume 17)
  - Day Book (Ore Bank), 7 June 1870 - 25 November 1873. (Volume 18)
  - Day Book (Ore Bank), 11 April 1874 - 17 November 1875. (Volume 19)
  - Ledger (Ore Bank), 1882-1883. (Volume 20)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 6 June 1870 - 10 April 1871. (Volume 21)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 11 April 1871 - 30 July 1872. (Volume 22)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 31 July 1872 - 17 June 1873. (Volume 23)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 18 June 1873 - 25 October 1873. (Volume 24)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 25 October 1873 - 24 March 1874. (Volume 25)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 24 March - 16 July 1874. (Volume 26)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 16 July - 24 October 1874. (Volume 27)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 24 October 1874 - 22 February 1875. (Volume 28)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 22 February 1875 - 28 July 1878. (Volume 29)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 28 May - 2 December 1879. (Volume 30)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 3 February - 11 October 1880. (Volume 31)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 11 October 1880 - 18 October 1881. (Volume 32)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 18 October 1881 - 2 December 1882. (Volume 33)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 2 December 1882 - 2 July 1883. (Volume 34)
  - Day Book (Amherst Furnace), 3 July 1883 - 8 December 1883. (Volume 35)
  - Ledger (Amherst Furnace), 1862-1865. (Volume 36)
  - Time Book (Amherst Furnace), January 1880 - February 1887. (Volume 37)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Journal (Day Book), 6 August 1889 - 17 August 1892. (Volume 38)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1889-1890. (Volume 39)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1889-1904. (Volume 40)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1891, 1901-1902. (Volume 41)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1902-1903. (Volume 42)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1904-1907. (Volume 43)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1910-1915. (Volume 44)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1910, 1938. (Volume 45)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Ledger, 1912-1913. (Volume 46)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Letter Book, 1890-1892 (Use Microfilm) (Volume 47)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Letter Book, 1892 (Use Microfilm) (Volume 48)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Letter Book, 1892-1894 (Use Microfilm) (Volume 49)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Letter Book, 1897-1898 (Use Microfilm) (Volume 50)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Minute Book, 1889-1904 (Use Microfilm) (Volume 51)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Stock Ledger, 1891-1904. (Volume 52)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Cash Ledger, 1891-1904. (Volume 53)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Day Book (Saddle Orders), 1892-1911. (Volume 54)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Order Book, 1902-1905. (Volume 55)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Order Book, 1904-1907, 1915. (Volume 56)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Order Book, 1914-1916. (Volume 57)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Inventory Ledger, 1892-1895. (Volume 58)
  - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company Hardware Inventory Ledger, n.d. (Volume 59)
  - Lexington Mill Ledger B, 1852. (Volume 60)
  - Day Book (North River Canal), 2 January 1871 - 13 September 1871. (Volume 61)
  - Day Book (Greensboro), 28 November 1877 - 28 May 1879. (Volume 62)
  - Buena Vista Cannery Ledger, 1888-1889. (Volume 63)
  - Check Register, 1888-1889. (Volume 64)
  - Ledger (G. W. Waesche), 1877-1879 (Volume 65)
  - Ledger (G. W. Waesche), n.d. (Volume 66)
  - Day Book (G. W. Waesche), 30 September 1878 - 12 August 1879. (Volume 67)
  - Morth River Insurance Company Policy Ledger, 1905-1907. (Volume 68)
  - Buena Vista Hotel and Cafe Guest Register, 1912-1914 (Volume 69)
- Series V. Joseph Gilmore Papers, 1752-1836., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 59-60)
  The Joseph Gilmore Papers, 1752-1836, relate to the activities of Joseph Gilmore, Sr. (ca. 1758-1830) of Rockbridge County, Virginia. This series is arranged alphabetically. It includes accounts and receipts, agreements, bills of sale, bonds, correspondence, deeds, estate papers of Thomas Lang, information on the sale and purchase of Gilmore's plantation "Sydney Vale," executions, fee bills, memorandum books, promissory notes, suit papers, surveys and land courses, and tax tickets.
  Some items of note in the collection include tax collector's instructions (1802), signed by Edward Carrington (1748-1810), circulars from the Grand State Lottery of Maryland (1821), Mutual Assurance Society printed laws, constitution, and rules and regulations (1795, 1805), rules and regulations of the Natural Bridge Light Dragoons (1836), and a small pox vaccination list (1820).
  The correspondence contains letters from relatives in Pulaski County, Kentucky, including James Gilmore (d. 1820) and John Gilmore (d. 1812), mainly involving family estate matters and land disputes.
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1771-1779. (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1780-1789. (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1790-1799. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1800-1809. (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1810-1819. (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1820-1829. (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Accounts and Receipts, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Agreements, 1805-1825. (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Almanac. (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Assignment, 1792. (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Bills of Sale. (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Bonds, 1774-1811. (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Breckenridge, James. (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Carrington, Edward (Collectors' Instructions, 1802. (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1795-1809. (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1810-1819. (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1820-1829, 1838. (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Deeds, 1802-1815. (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Estate of Thomas Lang. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Executions, 1805-1821. (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Fee Bills, 1779-1822. (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Grand State Lottery of Maryland. (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Land Entries. (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Memoranda. (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Memorandum Books. (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Miller, John. (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Muster Fines. (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Mutual Assurance Society. (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Natural Bridge Light Dragoons - Rules and Regulations, 1836. (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods. (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Powers of Attorney. (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Promissory Notes, 1772-1826. (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Recipes. (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Sheriff's Bonds, 1824. (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Sheriff's Order, 1828. (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Small Pox Vaccination List, 1820. (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - Suit Papers. (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - Surveys and Land Courses. (Box 60, Folder 21)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1782-1828. (Box 60, Folder 22)
  - Tobacco and Flour Sales. (Box 60, Folder 23)
- Series VI. Oversize, 1780-1900., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 61-62)
  The oversize series contains many of the same topics as can be found in the Subject Files. There are accounts and receipts, architectural drawings and plans, Buena Vista post office letter registers (1855-1864), Grand State Lottery of Maryland circulars, estate papers of Samuel F. Jordan, a Freemason's certificate (1780), land grants, Mutual Assurance Society policy (1803), presidential pardon (1865), life insurance policies of the Waesche family, and tax and duty abstracts (1800-1802).
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1848. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1849. (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1850-1851. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Ben Hur Souvenir Album, 1900. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Cohen's Gazette and Lottery Register, 1821, 1826. (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - J. Compton and Son - Accounts, 1853-1860. (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Compton and Chandler - Accounts, 1853-1857. (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Compton, Jordan and Co. - Accounts, 1839. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Samuel F. Jordan. (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Foundry Book Accounts to Collect, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Freemason Certificate, 1780. (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Gardner, John - Accounts, 1868-1883. (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - C. F. Jordan Credits, 1858-1868. (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Mutual Assurance Society, 1803. (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Presidential Pardon, 1865. (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Rockbridge Baths Insurance Policy, 1888. (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Stevens, William - Accounts, 1848-1855. (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - R. H. Stratton, Brown and Stratton, Jordan and Stratton - Accounts, 1847-1855. (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Waesche - Life Insurance. (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Willson and Compton - Accounts, 1866-1868. (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Wilson, John M. - Accounts, 1849-1851. (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Yount, Samuel - Accounts, 1852-1864. (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Architectural Plans and Drawings. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Deeds. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Diplomas. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Duty Abstracts, 1800-1802. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - General Orders, 1862. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Land Grants. (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Maps of Buena Vista, 1890. (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Post Office, 1855-1864. (Box 61, Folder 1)
- Series VII. Ephemera., Extent: 1 box. (Box 63)
  There is one small box of ephemera containing leather samples, coins, purses and wallets, and saddle hardware, such as buttons, buckles, and rivets, and other miscellaneous items.
  - Ephemera. (Box 63)